Guide to the International War Crimes Tribunal records, 1967, 1970
International War Crimes Tribunal records, 1967, 1970
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
International War Crimes Tribunal records, 1967, 1970.
4285
2.4 cubic ft.
Statements, correspondence, reports, testimonies, photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Tribunal records include mimeographs, edited versions, and final drafts of testimonies, reports, opening and closing statements, and summaries of the Stockholm and Copenhagen sessions (1967); also, press releases, copies of correspondence, photographs, speeches, agendas, and statutes. In addition, there are materials pertaining to the National Liberation Front; reports of the Commission for the Denunciation of U.S. War Crimes in South Vietnam (1970); and reports, printed matter, and other materials concerning the International Commission of Enquiry into U.S. Crimes in Indochina.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
The International War Crimes Tribunal was sponsored by the Bertrand Russell Peace Foundation to provide a forum for testimony and evidence concerning the damaging effects of U.S. policy in Indochina.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Tribunal records include mimeographs, edited versions, and final drafts of testimonies, reports, opening and closing statements, and summaries of the Stockholm and Copenhagen sessions (1967); also, press releases, copies of correspondence, photographs, speeches, agendas, and statutes. In addition, there are materials pertaining to the National Liberation Front; reports of the Commission for the Denunciation of U.S. War Crimes in South Vietnam (1970); and reports, printed matter, and other materials concerning the International Commission of Enquiry into U.S. Crimes in Indochina.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Behar, Abraham.; Burchett, Wilfred G., 1911-; Caldwell, Malcolm.; Chaliand, Gérard, 1934-; Chesneaux, Jean.; Faulkner, Stanley.; Fourniau, Charles.; Gaulle, Charles de, 1890-1970.; Halimi, Gisèle.; Kais¸¯on Phomvih¯an.; Kolko, Gabriel.; Norodom Sihanouk, 1922-; Pic, Roger.; Riffaud, Madeleine.; Russell, Bertrand, 1872-1970.; Sartre, Jean Paul, 1905-; Thanh Savanvilay.; Thiounn Prasith.; Bertrand Russell Peace Foundation.; Commission for the Denunciation of U.S. War Crimes in South Vietnam.; International Commission of Enquiry into U.S. Crimes in Indochina.; Mat trân dân tôc gi?ai phóng mi`ên nam Viêt Nam.; Vietnam (Democratic Republic).?Uy ban di`êu tra tôi ác chi ´ên tranh c?ua d`ê qu´ôc M~y ?o´ Viêt-Nam.; Vietnam (Provisional Revolutionary Government, 1969-1975)
Titles:
Against the crime of silence: proceedings of the Russell International War Crimes Tribunal.
Subjects:
Biological warfare.; Prisoners of war.; Vietnamese Conflict, 1961-1975--Atrocities.; Vietnamese Conflict, 1961-1975--Chemical warfare.; War crimes.; War (International law); War--Protection of civilians.
Places:
Cambodia.; Laos.; Thailand.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Testimonies.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- I. International War Crimes Tribunal - The Evidence of Stockholm, 1967
  - Editor's Preface. Duffett, John. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Inaugural Statement. Sartre, Jean Paul. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Inaugural Statement to the First Tribunal Session. Russell, Bertrand. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence with heads of state. Gaulle, Charles de; Sartre, Jean Paul. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Trial of Japanese War Criminals - Tokoyo 1946-1948 ," testimony by Jean Chesneaux. Chesneaux, Jean. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Summary of Historical Report." Kolko, Gabriel. (Box 1, Folder 4-6)
  - "American Intervention in Vietnam - 1954-1964 ," testimony by Jean Chesneaux. Chesneaux, Jean. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Historical Report on U.S. Aggression in Vietnam - 1964-1967 ," testimony by Charles Fourniau. Fourniau, Charles. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "International Law and the Military Draft," testimony by Stanley Faulkner. Faulkner, Stanley. (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
  - "Summary of a Juridical Report," by Samuel Rosenwein. Rosenwein, Samuel. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Judicial Report of Aggression in Vietnam," testimony by the Japanese Legal Committee. Japan Committee for the Investigation of U.S. War Crimes in Vietnam. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Report from Cambodia," testimony by Bernard Couret. Couret, Bernard. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Report from Cambodia and North Vietnam," testimony by Tarig Ali. Ali, Tarig. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "On Cambodia," testimony by Mme. Rena Kahn. Kahn, Rena. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "Testimony on Cambodia," by Wilfred Burchett, Burchett, Wilfred G. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "Questioning of a Khmer Mercenary." Kahn, M. Francis. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "Extracts from a Summary Report on the Bombing of the Civil Population in the North," testimony by Abraham Behar, M.D. Behar, Abraham. (Box 1, Folder 18-19)
  - "Non-Military Targets and Methods of Attack," testimony by Y. Ishijima. Ishijima, Y. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "Bombardment of Civilians in North Vietnam," testimony by John Takman, M.D. and Axel Hojer, M.D. Hojer, Axel; Takman, John. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "American Bombing in North Vietnam," testimony by Jean Michel Krivine, M.D. Krivine, Jean Michel. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - "On the Destruction of the Leprosarium of Quinh Lap," testimony by M. Francis Kahn. Kahn, M. Francis. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - "Report on Civilian Bombardment," testimony by Professor S. Kugai. Kugai, S. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - "Report from North and South Vietnam," testimony by Marta Rojas. Rojas, Martha. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "Extracts from the Testimony of Alejo Carpentier." Carpentier, Alejo. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - "Investigations of U.S. War Crimes in Vietnam," testimony by Lawrence Daly. Daly, Lawrence. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - "Report on Bombing of North Vietnam," testimony by Charles Cobb and Julius Lester. Birnstingl, Martin; Cobb, Charles; Lester, Julius. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - "Effects of the Aggression Against the DRV on Public Health," testimony by Roberto Guerra, M.D. Guerra, Roberto. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - "Testimony and Medical Report of Vietnamese Victims." (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - "Examinations of Wounded from U.S.Bombing," testimony by Henrik Fross, M.D. Fross, Henrik. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - "Report on the Destruction of Dikes: Holland 1944-1945 and Korea 1953 ," testimony by Professor Gabriel Kolko. Kolko, Gabriel. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - "Significance of the Destruction of Dikes in North Vietnam," testimony by Professor Fujio Yamazaki. Yamazaki, Fujio. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - "Some Facts on Bombing of Dikes," testimony by Professor Makato Kandachi. Kandachi, Makato. (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - "Bombing of Dikes and Irrigation Systems in the DRV," testimony by Tsetsure Tsurushima. Tsurushima, Tsetsure. (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - "On the Law of Land Warfare," testimony by Frank Pestana. Pestana, Frank. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - "Extracts from 'Fundamentals of Aerospace Weapons Sysytems'" (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - "Technical Aspects of Fragmentation Bombs," testimony by Jean Pierre Vigier, M.D. Vigier, Jean Pierre. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - "Combined Report on Anti-Personnel Bombs," testimony by Members of the Japanese Scientific Committee. Japan Committee for the Investigation of U.S. War Crimes in Vietnam. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - "Effects of Anti-Personnel Bombs on the Human Body," testimony by F. Mazas and J. Zucman. Mazas, F.; Zucman, J. (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - "Statement on the Pentagon's Denial of the Use of CBUs," by Vladimir Dedijer. Dedijer, Vladimir. (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - "Report from North Vietnam on Civil Bombardment," testimony by J.B. Nielands. (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - "The Bombing of Dai Lai," testimony by Gerard Chaliand. Chaliand, Gerard. (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - "Verdict of the Stockholm Session." (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - "Closing Address to the Stockholm Session," by Bertrand Russell. Russell, Bertrand. (Box 1, Folder 44)
- II. International War Crimes Tribunal - The Evidence of Copenhagen, 1967
  - "Opening Statement to the Second Tribunal Session," by Bertrand Russell. Russell, Bertrand. (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - "Opening Address to the Second Session," by Jean Paul Sartre. Sartre, Jean Paul. (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - "Greetings to the Tribunal from American Supporters," address by Carl Oglesby. Oglesby, Carl. (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - "Report on the Law of War," testimony by Yves Jouffa. Jouffa, Yves. (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - "Incendiary Weapons, Poision Gas, Defoliants Used in Vietnam," testimony by Abraham Behar, M.D. Behar, Abraham. (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - "On Chemical and Biological Warfare in Vietnam," testimony by Alexander Minkowski, M.D. Minkowski, M.D. (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - "Report of the Sub-Committee on Chemical Warfare in Vietnam." Lederer, Edgar. (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - "Extracts from a Report on Agricultural Chemicals Used in Vietnam," testimony by the Japanese Scientific Committee. Japan Committee for the Investigatio of U.S. War Crimes in Vietnam. (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - "Patterns of Bombing Civilans in the North," testimony by Wilfred Burchett. Burchett, Wilfred G. (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - "Escalating Bombardment of North Vietnamese Cities," testimony by Antonello Trombadori. Trambadori, Antonello. (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - "Judicial Report on the Treatment of War Prisoners and Civilians," testimony by Solange Bouvier Ajam. Ajam, Sloange Bouvier. (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - "Testimony and Questioning of David Kenneth Tuck." Tuck, David Kenneth. (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - "Testimony and Questioning of Peter Martinsen." Martinsen, Peter. (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - "Testimony and Questioning of Donald Duncan." Duncan, Donald. (Box 1, Folder 56-58)
  - "Report of the Commission of Inquiey to the United States," testimony by Gisele Halimi. Halimi, Gisele. (Box 1, Folder 59-60)
  - "Study on the Erosion of Moral Constraint in the Vietnam War," testimony complied by Clergy and Laymen concerned about Vietnam. Clergy and Laymen concerned about Vietnam. (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - "A Doctor Reports from South Vietnam," testimony by Erich Wullf. Wullf, Erich. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Report on American Conduct of the War in the South," testimony by Jean Bertolino. Bertolino, Jean. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "On Treatment of Civilians," testimony by Joris Ivens and Marceline Loridon. Ivens, Joris; Loridon, Marceline. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "On the Treatment of Women and Children in the South," testimony by Madeleine Riffaud. Riffaud, Madeleine. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "Imprsionment and Torture of Political Prisioners," testimony by Pham Thi Yen. Pham Thi Yen. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "Depositions Taken Concerning South Vietnam," from testimony by Hugh Manes. Manes, Hugh. (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
  - "Report of the Seventh Inquiry Commission Concerning the Zones in the South under NLF Control," testimony by Roger Pic. Pic, Roger. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "Summary Report on Complicity of Thailand and the Philippines," from testimony by Charles Fourniau. Fourniau, Charles. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - "Complicity of Thailand in the U.S. Aggression," testimony of the Japanese Commission. Japan Committee for the Investigation of U.S. War Crimes in Vietnam. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "Combined Report on the Complicity of Japan in the Vietnam War," testimony by the Japanese Committee. Japan Committee for the Investigation of U.S. War Crimes in Vietnam. (Box 2, Folder 11-12)
  - "The United States and Laos," testimony by Wilfred Burchett. Burchett, Wilfred G. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - "U.S. Actions against Laos," testimony by Lt. Guillermo Frank Llanes. Llanes, Guillermo Frank. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "On Genecide," by Jean Paul Sartre. Sartre, Jean Paul. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Summation on Genocide," by Lelio Basso. Basso, Lelio. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Summary and Verdict of the Second Session." (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Appeal to American and World Opinion," read by Dave Dellinger. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "Bertrand Russell's Final Address to the Tribunal, Copenhagen, Dec. 1967 ." Russell, Bertrand. (Box 2, Folder 17)
- III. Miscellaneous Materials relating to the International War Crimes Tribunal
  - Miscellaneous Vietnamese sources. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - National Liberation Front statements and testimony. National Liberation Front. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - National Liberation Front reports. National Liberation Front. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Reports of the Commission for the Denunciation of U.S. War Crimes in South Vietnam.. Commission for the Denunciation of U.S. War Crimes in South Vietnam. (Box 2, Folder 21-22)
  - Report by Dr. Pam Ngoc Thach. Pham Ngoc Thanch. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Press releases. (Box 2, Folder 24-25)
  - Miscellaneous statements and speeches regarding the Russell War Crimes Tribunal. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Agendas, statutes, and other materials pertaining to the Tribunal. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Reports on genocide. Aybar, Mehmet Ali; Matarasso, L.; Alvarez Tabio, Fernando. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Testimonies and reports not appearing in Against the Crime of Silence: Proceedings of the Russell International War Crimes Tribunal. Caldwell, Malcom; Lacostw, Yves. (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Testimonies and reports not appearing in Against the Crime of Silence: Proceedings of the Russell International War Crimes Tribunal. Ilkon, Paik; Matarasso, L. (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Testimonies and reports by individuals for whom other reports appear in Against the Crime of Silence. Burchett, Wilfred G.; Pic, Roger. (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Testimonies and reports by individulas for whom other reports appear in Against the Crime of Silence. Cini, Marcello; Halimi, Gisele; Kahn, M. Francis; Llanes, Guillermo Frank. (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Japanese evidence (see alos various testimonies in Against the Crime of Silence). Funazaki, Zenzaburo; Yoshizawa, Hiroki; Nagoya People's Tribunal; Tokyo Tribunal. (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Japanese evidence (see also various testimonies in Against the Crime of Silence). Shibata Shingo. (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Cambodian evidence. Thiounn Prasith; Norodom Sihanouk, Prince. (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Laos. Kaysone Phomvihane; Thanh Savanvilay. (Box 2, Folder 36)
- IV. International Commission of Enquiry into U.S. Crimes in Indo china - Stockholm, 1970
  - Materials from "Republic of South Vietnam." Provisional Revolutionary Governemnt of South Vietnam. (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Democratic Republic of Vietnam materials. Provisional Revolutionary Government of South Vietnam. (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Reports from Western sources. Frank, Hans Goran; Poltorak, Arkady; Provisional Revolutionary Governemnt of South Vietnam. (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Published materials. Provisional Revolutionary Governemnt of South Vietnam. (Box 2, Folder 40)
- V. Photographs
  - Prints and negatives taken during the International War Crimes Tribunal. (Box 3)